

Muhasin Uddin Mahmud Full Stack Web Developer

ABOUT ME

Experienced Full-Stack Web Developer with a Master's degree in Usability Engineering and almost 5 years of experience. Expert in multiple programming languages, software development methodologies, and database management systems. Looking to join a dynamic team where I can use my problem-solving skills and teamwork to drive innovation and achieve company goals.

January 16, 1989 in Madaripur, Bangladesh

mahmudmuhasin@gmail.com

+49 15774134901

Eisenstraße 5640227 Düsseldorf, Germany

DRIVING LICENSE

B

LANGUAGES

English: Expert

German: Intermediate

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2022 - present

JUNIOR TRAINER WEB DEVELOPMENT Digital Career Institute (DCI)

Düsseldorf

Teach full stack web development with a focus on the MERN stack, oversee student projects, and offer mentorship to support their progression in web development.

January 2021 - present

IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST (PART TIME)

Healthy Smile Dental Care

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Developed and have been maintaining the official website for Healthy Smile Dhaka, a renowned dental clinic in Bangladesh, since 2021

February 2022 - June 2022

JUNIOR TEST AUTOMATION ENGINEER / JUNIOR TRAINER WEB DEVELOPMENT

Digital Career Institute (DCI)

Düsseldorf

Developed automation code to test students' exercises besides teaching.

June 2021 - February 2022

ASSISTANT TRAINER WEB DEVELOPMENT

Digital Career Institute (DCI)

Düsseldorf

Assisted in teaching web development courses and provided support for student projects.

Conducted workshops and coding sessions.

Supported the teaching team in delivering full-stack web development curriculum.

May 2012 - April 2013

ASSOCIATE RESEARCHER

University Grant Commission of Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Participated in a research project entitled "Mental health in relation to the environmental noises at high-rise buildings."

EDUCATION

2020 - 2021

SOFTWARE AND WEB DEVELOPMENT WEITERBILDUNG

Digital Career Institute (DCI), Full-stack web development

Düsseldorf, Germany

Completed a 14-month intensive course focused on enhancing programming proficiency through multiple projects. Specialized in the MERN stack, with a strong emphasis on software methodologies, indi-

vidual project development, and deployment skills.

2018 - 2020

MASTER

Rhine-Waal University of A p p lied Sciences Germany, Usability Engineering

Kamp-Lintfort, Germany

Master thesis: The correlation between changes in mental representation structures and corresponding gaze behavior.

2020 - 2020

ORIENTATION IN TECHNICAL CAREERS

Digital Career Institute (DCI)

Düsseldorf, Germany

Completed a four-week orientation course in the digital economy.

2007 - 2012

BACHELOR

Jagannath University, Dhaka, Psychology

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SKILLS



TRAIN THE TRAINER

- Introduction to pedagogical techniques and educational theory
- Introduction of methods to assist in effective lesson design
- Exercises designed to improve lecturing skills and knowledge transfer

GITHUB

https://github.com/muhasin-m

LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhasin-uddin-mahmud-5b6639164/

HOBBIES

Traveling to explore new cultures and landscapes, and enjoying outdoor activities to connect with nature.

CV - Muhasin Uddin Mahmud 2/2